Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're bringing you the third part of this series that we've created called I'm
今天我们为大家带来这个系列的第三部分，我们称之为《对不起，我爱你》。
Sorry I Love You.
《对不起，我爱你》。
That's right.
没错。
The third part in our story about our EnglishPod couple.
这是我们EnglishPod情侣故事的第三部分。
Yeah, it's a romantic series, but today we're bringing you an argument.
是的，这是一个浪漫系列，但今天我们带来了一场争吵。
That's right.
没错。
Like in every relationship, you have fights, you have discussions, so we're going to teach
就像每段感情一样，你们会吵架，会争论，所以我们要教
you how to do that in English.
你如何用英语处理这些情况。
That's right.
没错。
And in today's lesson, you'll learn some great language that people use when they get into
在今天的课程中，你将学到一些很棒的表达，人们在与男朋友或女朋友
an argument with their boyfriend or girlfriend.
发生争执时会用到这些表达。
Right.
对。
So why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview.
那么我们先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
We have one phrase today.
今天有一个短语。
Get a hold.
Get a hold。
联系上。
Get a hold.
To get a hold.
联系上。
To get a hold of someone means...
联系上某人意味着……
To try and communicate with that person.
试图与那个人沟通。
Exactly.
没错。
So to try and call that person.
所以就是试着给那个人打电话。
For example, I can say, I've been calling his phone all day, but I can't get a hold
例如，我可以说，我一整天都在打他的电话，但联系不上
of him.
他。
Or I could say, finally, Marco, I got a hold of you.
或者我可以说，终于，Marco，我联系上你了。
Where have you been all day?
你一整天都去哪儿了？
Exactly.
没错。
Now we're going to listen to our dialogue and as always, it's going to be at a normal
现在我们要听对话了，和往常一样，会以正常语速播放，
pace, but you don't have to worry about it.
但你不用担心。
We'll come back and teach you all of the important words.
我们会回来教你所有重要的词汇。
There was an emergency at work, so...
工作上出了点紧急情况，所以……
Honey, I promise this won't happen again.
亲爱的，我保证不会再发生了。
It's just that I...
只是我……
I'm tired of you putting your job first all the time.
我受够了你总是把工作放在第一位。
Come on, Veronica.
拜托，维罗妮卡。
That's not fair.
这不公平。
I do care about you a lot.
我真的很在乎你。
You know that.
你知道的。
I try to...
我试着……
You know what?
你知道吗？
Maybe we should just take a break.
也许我们该暂时分开一下。
I need some time to think about where this relationship is heading.
我需要一些时间来思考这段关系的发展方向。
But Veronica, would you listen to me?
但是维罗妮卡，你能听我说吗？
There was a fire alarm at my office building today and I was...
今天我们办公楼的火警响了，我……
Okay so a little bit of trouble in the relationship.
好吧，看来这段关系出了点小问题。
Yeah, that's too bad.
是啊，那太糟糕了。
Yeah, well, I think she's overreacting.
嗯，我觉得她反应过度了。
You do?
你这么认为？
We'll talk about that later on.
我们稍后再谈这个。
But we saw some great words and phrases here, so it's time for Language Takeaway.
但我们在这里看到了一些很棒的单词和短语，所以现在是语言总结时间。
Language Takeaway.
语言总结。
Today on Language Takeaway, we're bringing you three words.
今天的语言总结，我们带来三个单词。
The first word is, stood me up.
第一个单词是，放我鸽子。
Stood me up.
放我鸽子。
放我鸽子了。
The phrase, stand someone up, when do we use this?
短语“放某人鸽子”，我们什么时候用这个？
If, for example, you have a date and you don't go.
比如，你有个约会但没去。
Okay, so let's say you and I were supposed to have dinner together and you just didn't
好，假设我们本来要一起吃晚饭，但你不仅没来
come and didn't call.
还没打电话。
Right, so I stood you up.
对，所以我放你鸽子了。
Okay.
好的。
Stand someone up.
放某人鸽子。
Our next word, priorities.
下一个词，优先事项。
Priorities.
优先事项。
So, priorities are something that's really important in your life.
所以，优先事项是你生活中非常重要的事情。
That's right, like family or maybe work or making a lot of money or whatever it is.
没错，比如家庭、工作、赚很多钱，或者别的什么。
What are your priorities in life, right?
你生活中的优先事项是什么，对吧？
Right, yeah.
对，是的。
Okay.
好的。
And our last word for Language Takeaway, heading.
我们语言摘录的最后一个词是“heading”。
Heading.
Heading。
This is a bit of a funny verb.
这个动词有点意思。
So let's listen to a couple of examples of how it's used so we can understand its meaning.
我们来听几个例子，看看它是怎么用的，这样就能理解它的意思了。
Example one.
例子一。
I don't know where our relationship is heading.
我不知道我们的关系会走向何方。
Example two.
例子二。
Where's this bus heading?
这辆公交车是开往哪里的？
Example three.
例子三。
Where's this project heading?
这个项目会朝什么方向发展？
So basically heading means going.
所以基本上 heading 就是 going 的意思。
Exactly.
没错。
A heading is where you're going.
标题就是你要去的地方。
Yep.
是的。
Okay, easy word and interesting.
好的，简单的词，很有趣。
Okay so now it's time for us to listen to the dialogue a second time.
好了，现在是我们第二次听对话的时候了。
It's going to be slower so now we can understand the words that we just talked about.
这次会慢一些，这样我们就能理解刚才讨论的单词了。
Stephen, where have you been?
斯蒂芬，你去哪儿了？
I've been trying to get a hold of you for hours.
我找了你几个小时了。
There was an emergency at work so...
工作上出了点紧急情况，所以……
I was waiting for you in the restaurant for three hours and you didn't even have the decency
我在餐厅等了你三个小时，你甚至连打个电话的礼貌都没有。
to call me.
给我打电话。
Do you have any idea how embarrassed I was?
你知道我有多尴尬吗？
Honey, I promise this won't happen again.
亲爱的，我保证不会再发生了。
It's just that I...
我只是……
Yeah, right.
是啊，说得对。
I've heard it all before.
这些话我都听腻了。
I'm not going to take any more of your empty promises.
我再也不会相信你的空头支票了。
This is the fifth time you've stood me up in two weeks.
这已经是两周内你第五次放我鸽子了。
You need to get your priorities straight.
你得搞清楚什么才是最重要的。
I'm tired of you putting your job first all the time.
我受够了你总是把工作放在第一位。
Come on, Veronica, that's not fair.
拜托，维罗妮卡，这不公平。
I do care about you a lot.
我真的很在乎你。
You know that.
你知道的。
I tried.
我试过了。
You know what?
你知道吗？
Maybe we should just take a break.
也许我们该暂时分开一下。
I need some time to think about where this relationship is heading.
我需要一些时间思考这段关系该何去何从。
But Veronica, would you just listen to me?
但是维罗妮卡，你能听我说吗？
There was a fire alarm at my office building today and I was stuck...
今天我们办公楼的火警响了，我被困住了……
Okay now we saw some interesting phrases in dialogue.
好了，我们在对话中看到了一些有趣的短语。
Yeah, we saw some great phrases that people use when they're getting in a fight.
是的，我们看到了一些人们在吵架时常用的好短语。
Why don't we take a look at some of them in Fluency Builder?
我们为什么不看看流利度构建器中的一些例子呢？
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
The first phrase that I want to take a look at today is, do you have any idea?
今天我想看的第一个短语是，你知道吗？
Do you have any idea?
你知道吗？
This is a great way to set up an argument.
这是展开争论的一个好方法。
So let's listen to some examples of how you would set up an argument using this phrase.
让我们听一些例子，看看如何用这个短语展开争论。
Example one.
例子一。
You forgot my birthday.
你忘了我的生日。
Do you have any idea how angry I am?
你知道我有多生气吗？
Example two.
例子二。
Julie kissed my boyfriend.
朱莉亲了我男朋友。
Does she have any idea how mean that was?
她知道那有多卑鄙吗？
Example three.
例子三。
I just broke up with my boyfriend.
我刚和男朋友分手了。
Don't you have any idea how sad I am?
你不知道我有多难过吗？
So it's a great phrase to make that person understand that you were really worried or
所以这是一个很好的短语，能让对方明白你真的很担心或者
really angry.
真的很生气。
Really angry.
Yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
Okay.
好的。
And now the second phrase that we can take a look at is, I've heard it all before.
现在我们可以看的第二个短语是，我早就听过了。
I've heard it all before.
我早就听过了。
So this is a great phrase of just saying, you don't have to give me an excuse.
这个短语很好用，意思就是，你不用给我找借口。
I know what you're going to say.
我知道你要说什么。
Exactly.
没错。
And our last phrase today, take a break.
今天我们最后一个短语，休息一下。
Take a break.
休息一下。
So when a couple takes a break, they sort of stop their relationship, right?
所以当一对情侣休息一下时，他们算是暂停关系，对吧？
They're breaking up.
他们分手了。
Yeah.
是的。
But is it really like forever?
但真的是永远吗？
Like a breakup that lasts forever?
像永远的分手？
Not, well, maybe.
不，嗯，也许吧。
It could be forever, but they're saying, let's just take some time away from each other for
可能是永远，但他们的意思是，咱们暂时分开一段时间，
a couple of days or weeks.
几天或几周。
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
And see what happens.
看看会发生什么。
Yes.
是的。
Take a break.
休息一下。
Okay.
好的。
So our happy couple is going to take a break.
所以我们的快乐情侣要休息一下。
Well, I guess they're not that happy then, hey?
嗯，我猜他们其实没那么快乐，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
So let's listen to their dialogue again, and then we'll come back and talk some more.
那我们再听一遍他们的对话，然后回来继续聊。
Stephen, where have you been?
斯蒂芬，你去哪儿了？
I've been trying to get a hold of you for hours.
我找了你几个小时了。
I, uh, there was an emergency at work, so...
我，呃，工作上有个急事，所以……
I was waiting for you in the restaurant for three hours, and you didn't even have the
我在餐厅等了你三个小时，你甚至连
decency to call me.
打个电话的礼貌都没有。
Do you have any idea how embarrassed I was?
你知道我有多尴尬吗？
Honey, I promise this won't happen again.
亲爱的，我保证不会再发生了。
It's just that I...
只是我……
Yeah, right.
是啊，说得倒好听。
I've heard it all before.
这些话我都听腻了。
I'm not going to take any more of your empty promises.
我再也不会相信你的空头承诺了。
This is the fifth time you stood me up in two weeks.
这是你两周内第五次放我鸽子了。
You need to get your priorities straight.
你得搞清楚什么才是最重要的。
I'm tired of you putting your job first all the time.
我受够了你总是把工作放在第一位。
Come on, Veronica.
拜托，维罗妮卡。
That's not fair.
这不公平。
I do care about you a lot.
我真的很在乎你。
You know that.
你知道的。
I try to...
我试着……
You know what?
你知道吗？
Maybe we should just take a break.
也许我们该暂时分开一下。
I need some time to think about where this relationship is heading.
我需要一些时间来思考这段关系的发展方向。
But, Veronica, would you listen to me?
但是，维罗妮卡，你能听我说吗？
There was a fire alarm at my office building today, and I was...
今天我们办公楼的火警响了，我正……
So, Marco, this phrase, to take a break, really reminds me of a Friends episode.
所以，马可，这个短语“休息一下”让我想起了一集《老友记》。
Yeah, that really famous Friends episode when Ross and Rachel were on a break.
是啊，就是那集著名的《老友记》，罗斯和瑞秋在休息期间。
And Ross, like, went with another girl, right?
然后罗斯就和另一个女孩在一起了，对吧？
Yeah, and then they definitely broke up after that.
对，之后他们肯定分手了。
Yeah.
嗯。
So that's one of the key issues, right?
所以这是关键问题之一，对吧？
If you're taking a break, can you start to date someone else?
如果你在休息期间，你能开始和别人约会吗？
I've got to agree with Rachel.
我不得不同意瑞秋的看法。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah. No, you can't.
是啊。不，你不能。
You can't?
你不能？
So what's the point of taking a break?
那休息一下有什么意义？
You need some time away.
你需要离开一段时间。
You need some time to think.
你需要一些时间思考。
But you're not really broken up.
但你们并没有真的分手。
Exactly.
没错。
That's convenient.
那可真方便。
I don't know.
我不知道。
They were on a break.
他们当时在分手期间。
I agree with Ross.
我同意罗斯的看法。
Well, you would, wouldn't you?
嗯，你当然会同意，不是吗？
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
We're out of time today.
今天时间到了。
I hope you enjoyed our lesson, and be sure to listen next time because we will definitely have a part four to this.
希望你喜欢我们的课程，下次一定要收听，因为我们肯定会有第四部分。
Yes.
是的。
Coming out soon.
即将推出。
Yep.
嗯。
And also come to our website at EnglishPod.com and leave all your questions and comments.
也请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，留下你的所有问题和评论。
Yeah, Marco and I are always happy to hear from you, and we love answering your questions.
是的，Marco 和我总是很高兴收到你的消息，我们喜欢回答你的问题。
Right, and maybe you can tell us what you think happens in the fourth part.
对，也许你可以告诉我们你认为第四部分会发生什么。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
Well, until then, it's...
那么，在那之前，这是……
Goodbye.
再见。
Bye.